原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译：草草 Reginamoon 王大可 油炸电风扇 勾勾 想名字好难 木浅
翻译：JohnnyG Alex Lynn_宁   校对：某羽 木浅薰
时间轴：姜姜   壬虚浪影  今
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第六季   第十三集
最新海外影视剧下载
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
Previously on Suits
-你想什么呢  -就是在想名字
- What you thinking about? - Just thinking about names.
如果我要一起养他
It's just that if I'm gonna help raise him,
我想给他点什么
I'd like to give him something.
他会跟你的姓
You're gonna be the one who gave him his last name.
但之后我的小儿子  他得了哮喘
My little guy--he got asthma.
客厅的窗户
The window in the living room--
已经坏了七个月了
it's been broken for seven months.
他的当事人欠了三个月房租
His client hasn't paid her rent in three months.
整个冬天房子都没暖气  还有扇窗户坏了
She's had no heat, and a broken window all winter
虽然她已经反复要求修理了
despite repeated requests for repair.
她的要求从未写在纸面上
We don't have it in writing,
而法庭要求的  就是纸面记录
which is what the court requires.
我请求一点时间与我上司协商
I'd like to request time to confer with my supervisor.
-你得帮他  -我做不到
- You have to help him. - I can't.
我们申请  如果明早十点没有收到支票
We are requesting permission to evict
则法庭允许将其驱逐
if we don't have a check by 10:00 a.M. tomorrow.
三千六百美金
$3,600.
应该够支付你近三个月的房租了
Should be enough to cover your rent for the last three months.
我不知道说什么了
I don't what to say.
-这是工作邀约  -等你毕业
- This is a job offer. When you graduate,
你得在通过品行考核
you're gonna have to pass the Character of Fitness test.
你觉得去你的律所工作
And you think working at your firm
比去我的律所工作更体面
looks better than working at mine.
你是想说哈维让我帮你
You're gonna tell me you had nothing to do
拿律师执照和你一点关系都没有吗
with Harvey asking me to help you get a law license.
她之前都没注意到我
I wasn't even on her radar.
我只想做一件事情  你却毁了它
I had one thing I wanted to do, and you ruined it for me,
只是因为你无法接受
just because you can't accept the fact
我不想回到你这里工作的事实
that I don't wanna come back here.
我并没想让你回来
I wasn't trying to get you back.
-我只是想帮你  -我不相信
- I was trying to help you. - I don't believe you.
别再来打扰我的生活
Stop messing with my life!
迈克  你怎么来了
Mike, what are you doing here?
我来为吼你去找吉布斯的事道歉
I came to apologize for yelling at you about going to Gibbs.
-没这必要的  -有必要
- You don't have to do that. - Yes, I do.
我知道你都是为我好
I know you only had my best interest at heart.
你一向如此
You always do, and...
我不该冲你发火的
I shouldn't have snapped at you.
我不该背着你去找她的
I shouldn't have gone to her behind your back.
没事
That's okay.
结果还不错
It kinda worked out.
进来  我们喝一杯
Come on in. Let's have a drink.
你跟我说说
You can tell me all about it.
开玩笑  法律诊所
You kidding me? A legal clinic?
吉布斯不是说
I thought Gibbs told you
她绝不会允许的吗
she'd never let that happen.
是啊  她会告诉人们我是骗子
Yeah, by telling people I was a fraud.
但唯一多年前就知道
Turns out the one guy who knew I was a fraud
我是骗子的人开了家诊所
from years ago runs the clinic.
他不仅愿意雇我
Not only was he willing to hire me,
还对此非常开心
he was happy about it.
看来犯罪真有回报
Seems like crime does pay.
当然了
You bet your ass it does.
-怎么  -你不会相信的
- What? - You're never gonna believe it,
但他们让我监督一个三年级的法律学生
but they have me supervising this third-year law student.
她觉得自己比我牛
She thinks she knows more than me.
-你是说你身边有个你  -她比我糟多了
- You mean you have a you. - She is so much worse than me.
她是不是老是提
Is she constantly talking about
自己的记忆力有多好
what a great memory she has?
衣着品味差  拿男人的包包
Dresses shitty? She have man purse?
说够没
Are you done?
怎么  你还急着去哪吗
Why? You have someplace you gotta be?
其实  我这会儿还不能
Actually, I am supposed to stay away
回我们的公寓
from our apartment for awhile.
总之  我对路易说"我不管
So anyway, I said to Louis, "I don't care
大部分律师是不是从大办公室起步
if most of the associates start in the bullpen.
我不会放弃我的办公室"
I'm not giving up my office."
太棒了  瑞秋  但这都第三杯夏敦埃葡萄酒了
That's great, Rachel, but I'm on my third glass of Chardonnay,
我想你叫我过来应该不是
and I don't think you called me over here
为了告诉我你提交了资格认证申请
to tell me you submitted your application to the Bar,
或是你对路易表明了态度吧
or that you're putting your foot down with Louis.
没错
You're right.
我叫你过来是为了告诉你
I called you over here to tell you that...
我对迈克表明了态度
I put my foot down with Mike.
你终于叫他选好一种发型别变来变去了吗
You finally told him to pick a hairstyle and stick with it?
不是
No.
我终于告诉他
I finally told him
他走之前曾对我做出了一个承诺
that he made me a promise before he went away,
现在他回来了
and now that he's back
又找到了挣钱的工作
and gainfully employed,
是时候该给我个名分了
it's time for him to make an honest woman of me.
瑞秋  我好为你高兴
Rachel, I'm so happy for you.
答案是好
And the answer's yes.
什么答案
What answer?
-我还没问你什么呢  -你问了
- I didn't ask you a question yet. - Yes, you did,
而且我很乐意做你的伴娘
and I'd be thrilled to be your maid of honor.
谢谢  唐娜
Thank you, Donna.
迈克  太棒了
Mike, that's great.
我为你高兴
I'm happy for you.
你还想做我的伴郎吗
Still up for being my best man?
绝不会错过
Wouldn't miss it for the world.
我们还去教堂吗
We going back to the church?
不  这次我们要在家里办
No, we're gonna do it at our place this time.
不  那不行
No, you can't do that.
我想要个小型  亲密的仪式
Yeah, we just wanna keep it small, intimate.
我理解  但我不提出让你在这儿办
I understand, but what kinda best man would I be
还算哪门子好伴郎啊
if I didn't offer for you to have it here?
要我说  你不提就真的很不好了
Pretty shitty one if you ask me.
所以  你来道歉
So basically you came here to apologize,
是为了不用在你的
so you didn't have to get married
小破烂公寓里结婚
at your shitty little apartment.
你觉得如果我们有更好的地点
You think that I'd ask you to be my best man
我还会找你做伴郎吗
if we had a better location?
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢  哈维
Thanks, Harvey.
现在我们只需要确保
Now all we need to do is make sure
-你这次不会逃婚  -有意思
- you don't skip out on this one. - Yeah, it's funny.
我们还得确保你不会在婚礼上...
We also need to make sure that you don't--
唐娜
Donna at the wedding.
你说什么
What did you just say?
你喉咙里卡了什么吗
You got something caught in your throat?
没有  我没事
No, I'm all good.
诉讼双雄 第六季 第十三集
怎么回事
What's this?
我们要庆祝
We're celebrating.
路易  你知道我不能喝香槟酒
Louis, you know I can't have champagne.
我知道  所以我们要喝的是
I know, which is why we're having
能买到的最好喝的苹果酒
the best sparkling apple cider money can buy.
那样的话
Well, in that case...
我们庆祝什么
What are we celebrating?
庆祝你这周第一次做B超
The fact that it's your first sonogram this week.
路易  关于B超的事
Louis, about the sonogram...
约书亚问他是否可以来
Joshua asked if he could be there.
-什么  -他是孩子的父亲
- What? - He's the baby's father.
他想参与他的生活
He wants to be in its life.
或是想参与你的生活
Or wants to be in your life.
路易  我选了你没选他
Louis, I chose you over him.
你不用担心这一点
You don't have to be worried about that.
如果你想让我说他不能来
And if you want me to say he can't be there for this,
那我会说的
then I will,
但他问了我  我觉得这要求也算合理
but he asked me, and I thought it was a fair request,
所以我得问问你
so I'm asking you.
好吧  他可以去
Yeah, he can be there.
-你确定吗  -不确定
- Are you sure? - No, I'm not,
但我知道这样做是正确的
but I know it's the right thing to do.
谢谢你
Thank you.
打扰  我需要...
Um, excuse me, I just need to--
你好呀  本杰明
Oh, hello, Benjamin.
你是过来摆弄我的硬盘的吗
Have you come to manipulate my hard drive?
调试我的处理器
Debug my processor?
还是重启我的主板
Reboot my motherboard?
拜托  让我安静的升级一下VOX系统就好
Please, I just need to update your VOX in peace.
假如我想升级我的播放系统
If I wanted my VOX updated,
我会去找一个比你有经验得多的人
I'd be talking to someone with a lot more experience than you.
鲍尔森女士  我知道你清楚这一点
Ms. Paulsen, I know you know this
但我要第37次提醒你...
but I will remind you for the 37th time--
VOX是我们的电脑操作系统
that VOX is our computer's operating system,
一个季度得升级一次
and it needs to be updated once a quarter.
一个季度才一次吗
Once a quarter?
我俩还没结婚你就这么冷淡了吗
What, are we married?
我得告诉你
'Cause I got news for you.
这台主机需要个新的记忆条
This main frame needs a new memory stick
一季度来一次肯定不够
a hell of a lot more than once a quarter.
好了  完事了
That's it. I'm finished.
我会一步步教你如何硬重启
I would walk you through the hard restart,
但恐怕刚刚那句话里你的关注点全是错的
but I'm afraid you'd focused on all the wrong words in that sentence.
不不  此时此刻
No no, right now
我只关注你"完事了"这一点
I'm just focused on the fact that you're finished.
把钱留在桌子上就好
Now leave your money on the table,
这样我就能看着你离开了
so I can watch you walk away.
介意告诉我刚刚那出是怎么回事吗
Mind telling me what that was all about?
你是指我对我们的技术小哥进行性暗示吗
You mean me making sexually suggestive comments to our IT guy?
人家有名字的  你知道吧
He has a name, you know.
我知道  但我不信你知道
I do, but I'd be shocked if you knew what it was.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
的确  哈维  重点是
No, Harvey, the point is,
我不是对他这么做
I'm not doing anything to him,
而是为他才这么做的
I'm doing it for him.
你又是怎么知道的
And how exactly do you figure that?
我知道
I figure that,
是因为本杰明帮别人升级都是远程操作的
because Benjamin updates everybody else's computers remotely,
但他一个季度会下来一次
and once a quarter he's down here,
假装自己不喜欢我的举动
pretending not to like my act,
所以除非你想要我调转枪口  拿你开涮
so unless you want me to focus my rapier-like wit on you,
不然你还是挪挪你那漂亮的小身子
I suggest you walk your pretty little self
回你的办公室去吧
back into your office.
本杰明  我知道他的名字
Benjamin. I knew it.
不  你不知道
No, you didn't.
迈克  谢天谢地你来了
Mike, thank God you're here.
索菲亚・普莱斯刚刚打电话来了
Sofia Price just called.
她从昨晚到现在一直在医院陪着他儿子
She's been in the hospital since last night with her son.
-他没事吧  -嗯  暂时没事
- Is he okay? - I think so, for now.
是犯了哮喘  她想让我转告你...
It was an asthma attack, but she wanted me to tell you that--
她没办法准时去交房租了
She couldn't drop off the check for her rent.
该死的...
Damn it, um...
打电话给她  告诉她我会去处理
Call her back. Tell her I'm on it.
迈克  等等
Mike, wait.
你用自己的钱帮她还了债  是不是
You covered what she owed with your own money, didn't you?
因为那可是很大一笔钱
Because that's above and beyond.
晚点再赞美我也不迟
We can talk about how awesome I am later.
现在  我得去确保
Right now, I need to make sure that
索菲亚的租金能在十点前交齐
Sofia's rent is paid by 10:00.
路易  我能和你谈谈吗
Louis, can I talk to you?
当然
Of course.
我...我不知道该怎么办
I--I don't even know what to do.
我的手在抖
My hands are shaking.
瑞秋  发生什么事了
Rachel, what's going on?
我不能当律师了
I'm not getting into the Bar.
-什么  太荒唐了  -读读这个
- What? That's ridiculous. - Read this.
经仔细审查您的申请
After careful review of your application,
品行考核委员会
the Character and Fitness committee
决定不予你面试机会
will not be granting you an interview?
这简直扯淡
This is bullshit!
是啊  我知道我肯定是得为自己辩护的
I know, because I knew I was gonna have to defend myself,
但我没想到
but I didn't think
他们甚至不给我为自己辩护的机会
I wasn't even gonna have the chance to defend myself.
-好吧  冷静  -我怎么冷静得了
- Okay, calm down. - How can I calm down?
我爸担心的就是这种情况
This is exactly what my dad was afraid of.
他说过他们会因为我和迈克的关系为难我
He said that they'd hold my relationship with Mike against me.
这不一定是因为迈克
You don't know this is about Mike.
当然是因为迈克  还能...
Of course it's about Mike. What--
还能是因为什么
what else would it be about?
可能是文件出错了
It could be a mix-up,
可能是因为笔误
some kind of clerical error.
可能是你表格没填对
You could've filled out the paperwork wrong.
我检查了十遍
I went over it ten times.
瑞秋  这件事肯定是事出有因的
Rachel, there is an explanation for this,
我会查个清清楚楚
and I'm gonna get to the bottom of it.
-你保证不了  -看着我
- You don't know that. - Look at me.
我保证会让你得到面试机会的  好吗
I promise you will get your interview, okay?
好吧
Okay.
哈维  我们遇到麻烦了
Harvey, we have a problem.
怎么了
What is it?
这事和迈克有关
This is about Mike.
当然是和迈克有关了
Of course it's about Mike.
所以瑞秋一离开我办公室我就到这来了
That's why I came here the second Rachel left my office.
你怎么和瑞秋说的
What'd you tell Rachel?
你觉得我会怎么和她说
What do you think I told her?
我告诉她一定是出了什么差错
I told her that it must be some kind of mistake,
但我俩都心知肚明这不是出错
but you and I both knows it's not,
这意味着你得解决这件事
which means you need to fix this.
没错  的确需要我解决这件事
Yeah, I do need to fix it,
我也会解决
and I will.
但一般  你不会来找我
Normally, instead of coming to me,
而会开足马力  一意孤行
you'd go full steam ahead and do something
让情况变得更糟
that makes the situation significantly worse.
有可能  你想表达什么
Possibly. What are you getting at?
你到底为什么来找我
Why did you come to me?
因为我们说过要一起管理这间律所
Because we said we'd run this firm together,
而想要做到这一点
and if we're gonna do that,
那我就得诚实地面对
then I have to be honest with myself
自己的强项和你的强项
of what I'm good at and what you're good at.
而你知道在这种事上我比你在行
And you know I'm better at this kinda thing than you are?
我知道
I do.
路易  这说明你确实成长了
Louis, that shows real growth.
谢谢  哈维  你没有不在乎
Thank you, Harvey. And it shows growth on your part
我刚刚承认的  对我来说
not to make light of the fact that I just admitted
很难承认的事说明
something that was...
你也成长了
very difficult for me to admit.
你是说我在任何方面都比你强这件事吗
You mean that I'm better at everything than you.
-我没有这么说  -真可惜
- That's not what I said. - Too bad,
我就是这么理解的
because that's what I heard.
好吧  哈维  说正事
Okay, Harvey, seriously,
现在不是你拿我开玩笑的时候
this is not about you having fun with me.
事关瑞秋
This is about Rachel.
我知道  如果我对处理这件事
I know it is, and if I weren't confident
不是把握十足
that I could take care of it,
我也不会拿你承认
I wouldn't be giving you a hard time
我在各个方面都比你强这事跟你开玩笑
for admitting how much better I am at everything than you.
妈的
God damn it.
抱歉  路易  我还得去展示我的过人之处
Sorry, Louis, gotta go be better at something.
回见
See you later.
-我有什么能为你效劳的  -是的  你有
- Can I help you? - Yes, you can.
我叫迈克・罗斯
My name's Mike Ross.
我是来代表索菲亚・普莱斯
I'm here on behalf of Sofia Price,
这是她欠你的委托人的所有租金
and this is every dime of rent she owes your client.
为什么要你送来给我呢
And why exactly are you bringing that to me?
你是个律师  不是房东
Because you're an attorney, not a landlord,
我不想有什么误会
and I don't want there to be any misunderstandings.
据我所知现在是10点18分
What I understand is that it's 10:18,
但你的委托人的时限是10点整
and your client had till 10:00.
你在跟我开玩笑吗
You have got to be shitting me.
我很确定不是
I most certainly am not,
也许你的委托人在欠付这么多个月租金前
and maybe your client should have thought of that
就应该想到这种结果
before not paying her rent all those months.
你以为我不知道你们在搞什么鬼吗
You think I don't know what's going on here?
你们想赶她走  然后就可以把这个房子
You're trying to get her out, so that you can get this place out
移出租金控制名单
from under rent control,
但我不会让你得逞的
but I'm not gonna let you get away with it.
不  事实上是
No, what's going on here
我的委托人已经厌倦了这个
is that my client is sick of having a troublemaker,
总是不好好付房租的麻烦精
who doesn't pay her rent, as a tenant.
听我说  你不能现在驱赶她
Listen to me, you cannot evict her now.
她的儿子进医院了
Her son is in the hospital.
这是我的工作
I have a job to do.
好了  关于你委托人的儿子我很抱歉
Now, I am sorry about your client's son,
但法庭上讲的很清楚了
but the court was very clear,
我也做不了什么了
and there's nothing more that I can do.
迈克  怎样了
Mike, what happened?
晚到了18分钟
Got there 18 minutes late.
那有什么关系  你拿着三个月的租金
What does it matter? You had three months back rent.
他们想把她赶出去然后脱离租金控制名单
They wanna kick her out to get out of rent control,
我们错过了时限
and now that we've missed the deadline,
我们就没有办法了
there's nothing we can do about it.
不  有的
Wrong, there is.
我想了一下  他们为什么这么着急
I got to thinking--why would they be in such a hurry
驱赶一个好不容易能付其租金的人
to evict somebody who can actually come up with the money?
他们不仅仅想要把她赶出去
They're not just trying to get her out.
他们是想把每个人都赶出去
They're trying to get everyone out.
正是
Exactly.
他们要拆除整栋建筑
They're gonna demolish that whole building.
我昨天晚上去过  工人们已经就位了
I was over there last night. The workers were already there,
也就是说他们已经开始了
which means they've already started.
懂了  你想反诉他们
I get it. You wanna hit 'em with a countersuit.
我想要跟他们一记重拳
I wanna nail their asses to the wall.
你们两个着手准备诉讼吧
Now you guys get to work on the suit.
我要去和纳森聊聊如何与此同时
I'm gonna go talk to Nathan about stopping Sofia's eviction
-阻止索菲亚被赶出来  -迈克
- from happening in the meantime. - Mike.
你不用去找纳森  我可以处理
You don't need to go to Nathan. I can handle this.
-听着  我很感激  -我理解的
- Listen, I appreciate that-- - I get it.
我那天表现很糟糕
I shit the bed the other day.
-奥利佛  -听着  迈克
- Oliver-- - Look, Mike.
我承认有时我在法庭上会慌乱
I admit, sometimes I get flustered in court.
但本案法律很明确  这很简单
But the law's clear on this. It's a layup.
如果我们有个待决诉讼  那就可以自动
If we have a pending lawsuit, it puts an automatic hold
将驱逐令延期
on the eviction.
我告诉你我能处理这件事
I'm telling you I can handle this.
拜托  让我弥补一下之前的错误吧
Please, let me make up for the other day.
好吧  那你还在等什么
Well, what are you waiting for?
赶紧去法院
Get your ass down to court.
搞定了立刻告诉我
Let me know as soon as it's done.
好了  本杰明  娱乐时间结束了
All right, Benjamin, playtime's over.
你到底对我的电脑做了什么
What the hell did you do to my computer?
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything to it,
只是提升了一下它的性能
other than increase its performance.
如果那能叫提升性能
If that's your idea of increasing performance,
那你真的要好好考虑一下自己的职业生涯了
then you ought to rethink your career,
因为那玩意现在宕机的次数比梅尔・吉布森
because that thing has crashed more times
周六夜场喝高后回家路上的断片次数还多
than Mel Gibson on his way home from a Saturday night.
等等  你是在笑吗
Wait a second, are you smiling?
当然不是  你在冲我发火
Of course not. You're yelling at me.
我怎么会笑
Why would I be smiling?
别拿谎话糊弄谎话精  本杰明
Don't bullshit a bull-shitter, Benjamin.
你肯定有什么目的  你最好现在就坦白
You're up to something, and you better come clean right now.
好吧  我本身想找个
Okay. I was hoping to do this
更加正式的场合这么做  但是
in a more formal environment, but...
请允许我介绍一下  真・唐娜
Allow me to introduce The Donna.
这是什么玩意
What the hell is that?
这是个数字版的你
It's a digital version of you,
存储了约一万条
with approximately 10,000 of your best quotes,
你的名句  俏皮话  和歇后语
witticisms, and zingers, packed into five gigahertz
共计5个G容量
of computing power.
所以你才会亲自去升级我的电脑
That's why you've been personally updating my computer
别人都是远程升级吗
and nobody else's?
是的  我已经秘密给你录音
Yes, I've been secretly recording you
两年了
for the better part of two years.
两年
Two years?
为什么是我
Why me?
因为每个人都希望
Because everyone always wishes
能在正确的时间说正确的话
they could say the right thing
而你就是整个宇宙中
at the right time, and you are the one woman
唯一每次都能做到的人
in the universe who says the right thing every time.
更不用说  毫无疑问
Now to mention, you are without a doubt
你是史上
the most amazing legal secretary
最迷人的法律秘书
in the history of everything.
本杰明  这是我听过的
Benjamin, that's the sweetest thing
最好听的话了
anyone's ever said to me.
好吧  不过你自己两周之前就这么说过
Okay, but you said it about yourself two weeks ago.
-我是这么说过  -所以
- That I did. - In that case,
唐娜・鲍尔森  我本来打算
Donna Paulsen, I wasn't gonna ask you this
过几周再问你这件事  不过你觉得
for another few weeks, but how would you feel about
和我一起把这件事当成商机来经营怎么样
pursuing this with me as a business opportunity?
我想想吧
Let me think about it.
但首先  这个东西借给我用几天
But first, let me borrow that thing for a few days.
想不想跟我说说
Wanna tell me why
为什么你在我助理的律师资格申请上
you're playing games with my associate's
耍把戏
admission to the Bar?
-你是哈维・斯派克特  -亲自驾到
- You're Harvey Specter. - In the flesh,
如果我离开的时候
and if I don't walk out of here
没有拿到预约
with an appointment in my hand,
我保证你明白我的厉害
you're gonna find out what that means,
因为瑞秋・赞恩有资格说明她的观点
because Rachel Zane deserves to make her case.
瑞秋・赞恩
Rachel Zane.
肯定是安排上出了问题
This is clearly a scheduling error.
抱歉  我会
Sorry. I will, uh,
把她的面谈定在两周后
set her interview for two weeks from today.
我本该说谢谢
I'd say thank you,
但这是你本来就该做的
but you should've done that in the first place.
但是我觉得她过不了关
I don't think she's gonna pass, though.
-你说什么  -我只是觉得你应该知道
- What'd you say? - I just thought you should know
投票必须委员会全体成员
the vote has to be unanimous
一致通过才行
among the members of the committee,
我有预感
and I have a sense that
至少有一个人会不同意
at least one isn't gonna say yes.
你原本就能把她驳回
Well, you could've just rejected her,
但你还自找麻烦把我弄来
but you went to the trouble to get me down here,
所以有话快说
so get to it.
我只是说
Well, I'm just saying...
如果有个人打算  比如
that if someone were to, say,
告我最大的竞争对手  金额足够大
sue my biggest competitor for enough money
使得他们的股价暴跌
so that their stock price plummets,
或许赞恩女士的机会能大有转机
perhaps Ms. Zane's chances would take a turn for the better.
是不是这么说
Let me get this straight,
你在道德委员会之中
you're on the Ethics Committee,
而你却在要求我做违法的事情
and you're asking me to do something illegal.
如果找到合法的理由去告他们就不违法
It's not illegal if you can find  a legitimate reason to sue them.
那这事情肯定另有内情
Then there's gotta be more to the story,
不然你用不着把我找来
or you wouldn't be calling me in here,
勒索我去做这件事情
blackmailing me into doing this.
内情就是
The more to the story is,
你一直对道德问题很模糊
you have a history of ethical ambiguity,
而我需要的就是这个
and that's what this requires.
你要么去做  要么不做
And you're either gonna do it, or you're not.
不论如何  正如我所说
Either way, like I said,
赞恩女士的面试在两周后
Ms. Zane's interview is in two weeks.
疏忽致险  开玩笑吗
Reckless endangerment? Is this a joke?
我保证  索菲亚・普莱斯现在可没在笑
I guarantee you, Sofia Price isn't laughing.
任何心智正常的法官
Well, any judge in his right mind
都会在法庭上嘲笑死你
is gonna laugh you out of court,
因为你压根不懂法律
because you don't understand the law.
不懂法的是你
No, you're the one that doesn't understand the law,
约翰逊女士
Ms. Johnson.
你在租客未撤离的情况下开始拆除工作
You started demolition with tenants still in your building.
致使一个三岁孩子住进了急诊室
You sent a three-year-old to the emergency room.
你在这儿做文章  我会对妈妈火力全开
You pursue this, I'm going straight after the mother,
使她成为疏忽方
and I'll turn her into the negligent party,
到时候她能留住儿子就不错了
and she'll be lucky to keep her son.
你要是这么做  我就会向法庭展示
You do that, and I'll show the court
你和市政签署了建筑计划
that you filed construction plans with the city,
声称该建筑已经无人居住
claiming that the building was empty,
这在刑法里是可以判刑的
which is punishable under the criminal code.
不  罗斯先生  你什么都不会展示的
No, Mr. Ross, you won't show them anything.
要展示的是他
He will.
你觉得我不会查你吗
Did you think I wouldn't check up on you
突然之间
when all of a sudden,
一个皇后区的法律诊所跟中城区律所一样
a Queens legal clinic starts acting like a Midtown law form.
我查了
Well, I did.
如果这件事上了法庭
And if this goes to trial,
他才是我要对付的人
he's the one I'm up against,
我们都知道上次发生了什么
and we all know what happened last time.
如果你只想跟我说这些就不会来了
You wouldn't be here if that's all you wanted to tell me.
不如赶紧不给我一个数字
So why don't you give me a number,
我转达给我的客户
and I'll take it to my client.
一万美金  一分钱都多不了
$10,000. Not a penny more.
我在中城区律所的经验告诉我
You see, all my experience at a Midtown law firm
你得到的授权是两万
tells me you're authorized to go to 20,
干脆咱们定两万五  完事大吉
so let's say 25 and call it a day.
两万五美金
$25,000?
刑事诉讼  琳达
Criminal charges, Linda.
如果我是你  我会像捡了便宜一样
So if I were you, I'd cut that check,
立刻签支票
consider it a bargain,
祈求上苍那个孩子的病情不会恶化
and hope to hell that little boy doesn't get worse.
运气怎样
Hey, any luck?
取决于你对这个词的定义了
Depends on your definition of the word.
我见到给瑞秋发函的那个混蛋了
I met with the asshole that sent the letter to Rachel.
我猜猜  你没能说服他
Let me guess, you couldn't convince him
给瑞秋安排面试
to give her an interview.
面试安排好了
No, I got her the interview,
但投票必须是全体通过
but the vote has to unanimous,
而他对他的投票标了价
and he's putting a price on his vote.
他想要什么
What does he want?
他想让我们针对他最大的竞争对手
He wants us to fabricate a lawsuit
捏造一个诉讼
against his biggest competitor.
上帝啊  这不是个要求
Jesus Christ, that's not an ask,
是犯罪行为
that's a criminal action.
你以为我不知道吗
You think I don't know that?
好吧  哈维  如果找到了合法诉讼理由
Okay, Harvey, if we find a legitimate suit,
就不算违法了
it doesn't have to be illegal,
而眼下这种情况  还是值得做的
which means, under the circumstances, maybe it's worth doing.
不了解事情的全部之前我什么也不会做的
I'm not doing shit until I know the full story on this guy.
哈维  现在摆在面前的是瑞秋的未来
Harvey, this is Rachel's future we're talking about.
我知道
Yeah, I know it is,
但他想要的不止这些
but I'm telling you this isn't all he wants,
但除非我弄清楚所有真相
and I'm not going to agree to anything
我是不会答应他的
until I know what the hell it really is.
所以我们怎么办
Well, what are we gonna do?
要做什么的不是我  是你
I'm not doing anything. You are.
我不懂
I don't understand.
路易  你能承认我善后的能力比你强
Louis, you were man enough to admit to me
可以  这很男人
that I'm better at fixing things.
而你也确实有些地方比我强
Well, you're better at something than me,
那就是金融交易
and it's called financial transactions.
我很感激这么说  哈维  但这很重要吗
I appreciate that, Harvey, but what does that matter?
这个人这样做是为了拉低别人的股价
This guy's doing this to drive down someone's stock price,
我想知道他这么做原因何在
and I wanna know why.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
我们怎么跟瑞秋说
What do we tell Rachel?
实话实说  就是文件出错
The truth-that it was a mix-up,
现在她已经拿到了面试日期
but now she's got a date on the books.
而你我得在这日期前搞定此事
And you and I need to fix this before then.
索菲亚
Sofia.
-他怎么样了  -他还好
- How is he? - He's okay.
他们说他过几天就能出来了
They said he should get out in a couple of days.
我有几个好消息
I have some good news.
我们的家能保住了吗
We can stay in our place?
不是
No.
但是你们有一个月的时间找新家
But you have a month to find a new place,
以及两万五千美元帮你们找
and a check for $25,000 to help you find it.
罗斯先生  我非常感激你做的一切
Mr. Ross, I'm grateful for everything you've done,
但玛莉莎跟我说如果我们能证明
but Marissa told me that if we could prove
AJ出事是他们的责任的话
what happened to AJ is their fault,
他们就必须要给钱
they'd have to pay.
他们已经给了啊
They are paying.
但他们至少该出够他的治疗费吧
Shouldn't they pay at least enough for his treatment?
他光明年的注射治疗费
His injections next year are gonna be
就要两万五千美元啊
$25,000 right there.
索菲亚  法庭有风险
Sofia, going to court is always risk.
我们的生活本来风险就不少
Our lives have been one risk after another.
可这支票不是风险啊  这是实实在在的钱
This check isn't a risk. This is real money.
如果我们赢了我们能拿多少
How much could we get if we win?
最高的话  五十万
Absolute best case-$500,000--
-但我跟你说  -拜托了  罗斯先生
- but I'm telling you... - Please, Mr. Ross.
他们已经害他成了这样
They did this to him,
如果我们有机会改变他的生活
and if we have a chance to change his life,
就得冒这个险
we need to take it.
那好吧
Okay.
路易  有什么能我帮忙的吗
Louis, can I help you?
我只是在回忆我以前站在这里
I was just thinking about when I stood here years ago,
告诉你  你进不了哈佛的时候
and I had to tell you that you weren't gonna get into Harvard.
你当时也以为你永远做不了律师了
You thought you'd never be a lawyer,
但我知道你会有办法的
but I knew you'd find a way.
你替我拿到了面试机会
You got me my interview.
是的
I did.
结果...
Turns out...
只是文件出错
It was just a mix-up.
谢谢你  路易
Thank you, Louis.
你觉得我还用就我和迈克的关系
Do you think I'm still gonna have to defend myself
为我自己进行辩护吗
about my relationship with Mike?
我不知道  瑞秋
I don't know, Rachel,
但我知道的是  无论付出什么代价
but I do know we're gonna do whatever it takes
我们都要保证你能成为一名律师
to make sure you become a lawyer.
我已经名花有主了
I'm seeing someone.
这些不是给你的  是给我未婚妻的
These aren't for you. They're for my fiancée.
但如果这能让你答应交易  那就留着好了
But if it'll get you to close this deal, you can keep 'em.
我可以给她再买一束
I'll just buy her another bouquet.
-我已经搞定了  -并没有
- I already closed this deal. - Turns out you didn't.
-你说话不算话啊  -计划赶不上变化
- That is bad faith. - Circumstances changed.
就今天和今晚之间能有什么变了
What the hell changed between today and tonight?
我的客户发现她儿子需要更进一步的治疗
My client found out that her son needs more treatment,
所以就需要更多钱
which means she needs more money.
我倒觉得是你客户
I think what happened is your client's seeing
发现有更大的利可图
an opportunity for a bigger payday,
而你无法说服她
and you can't control her.
你怎么想的并不重要
Well, what you think doesn't really matter.
如果你不把协议金额加到十万
If you don't raise your offer to $100,000,
那我们就法庭见
we're going to court.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
这儿可不是华尔街
This isn't Wall Street.
我们不会给这么多的
We don't give out that kind of money.
可如果你输了  你们要给的
If you lose, you're going to be giving out
就比这多得多了
a hell of a lot more than that.
可如果我同意了
And if I agree to this,
你明天就会得寸进尺  要的更多
you'll be right back here tomorrow, asking for more.
听着  我打包票
Look, I'm telling you,
肯定能说服她同意这个条件的
I can get her to agree to this.
那我也明确告诉你  我条件已经开过了
And I am telling you, you've had your offer.
你能拿到的就这么多
That's all your gonna get,
如果你现在不接受  那就法庭见
and if you don't take it right now, we're going to trial,
我要让那孩子翻不了身
and I am gonna wipe the floor with this kid.
这我可不敢说
I wouldn't be so sure about that.
听我说
Listen to me,
如果你觉得你能耍些小手段
if you think you're gonna pull some kind of trick
让你坐在他旁边和他手挽手一起面对的话
to get you to be able to sit next to him and hold his hand,
那是不可能的
there's no way that's gonna happen,
因为你已经是个铁打的诈欺犯了
because you were deemed a fraud,
没有法官会让你把他自己的法庭
and no judge in the world is gonna let you
搅成一个笑话的
turn his court into a joke.
天呐  哈维的字也太丑了
Jesus Christ, Harvey's handwriting is so bad,
我的医生跟他比起来就像书法家了
he makes my doctor look like a calligrapher.
别说了  姐们
You're telling me, sister.
他的笔迹比梅尔・吉布森的周六夜晚还糟糕
That handwriting's sloppier than Mel Gibson on a Saturday night.
我了个去  你能根据现实这么快应用我的话
Holy shit, you can adjust my phrases to the situation at hand?
当然能了
Of course I can.
你以为你是在和谁打交道
Who do you think you're dealing with?
实际上
As a matter of fact,
我刚刚把"我了个去"加进我的词库里
I just incorporated "Holy shit" into my vocabulary right now.
不可能  这个词早就该有了
No way, that had to have already been in there.
看看是谁终于出现在派对上了
Well, look who finally showed up to the party.
《派对》由真・唐娜自编自导自演
"The Party," written by, produced by, and starring The Donna.
我喜欢你的想法
I like the way you think.
当然了  我就是你
Of course you do. I'm you.
你知道你的表现如何吗  棒呆了
And you know what you are? Awesome.
你想休息一下喝杯咖啡吗
You want to take a coffee break?
我觉得这是我们该得的
I think we've earned it.
我也是这么想的
Yeah. Me too.
坚决不喝格蕾琴喜欢的克里格的咖啡机
And none of that Keurig shit that Gretchen likes.
要么喝鲜煮的  要么就不喝
Fresh brewed, or nothing.
你什么时候变得这么泼辣了
When did you get so sassy?
哈维  太好了  你来了
Harvey, good, you're here.
我收到你的消息了  你发现什么了吗
I got your message. Did you find something?
你觉得呢
You tell me.
-这能解释很多问题  是不是  -没错
- Explains a lot, doesn't it? - It does.
干得漂亮  我就从这接手了
Good work. I'll take it from here.
-等等  你要去哪  -你觉得呢
- Wait, where are you going? - Where do you think I'm going?
我要去会会这个混蛋  跟他说清楚
I'm gonna see that asshole and set him straight.
但我给你点了个三明治
But I ordered you a sandwich--
火鸡肉不要蛋黄酱多加酸黄瓜  你最爱的
turkey, no mayo, extra pickles, like you like it.
你到底想不想让我解决瑞秋的问题了
Do you want me to fix Rachel's problem or not?
我想  只是...
I do. It's just...
我以为我们能谈谈
I thought we could talk.
你是指谈什么
What do you mean talk?
哈维  求你了  我需要一场男人间的对话
Harvey, please, I need to talk to you man-to-man.
不是工作上的事
It's not about business.
你真的给我点的多加酸黄瓜
Did you really get me extra pickles?
唐娜以前告诉过我你好这口
Donna once told me that's what you like.
好吧  路易  我有点时间
Okay, Louis, I got a few minutes.
你真的能辨别出来是不是鲜煮的
You really can tell if it's fresh brewed or not?
拜托  我可是个老手了
Please, this isn't my first rodeo.
可不是吗
You're telling me.
唐娜  我能跟你谈谈吗
Donna, could I talk to you for a second?
当然了  你需要什么  美女
Of course you can. What do you need, hot pants?
这是什么
What--what is that?
一个叫真・唐娜的设备
It's a device called The Donna
本杰明搞的  帅呆了
that Benjamin's working on, and it's awesome.
来吧  随便问它
Go ahead, ask it something.
我不想问它
I don't wanna ask it something.
我想问你
I wanna ask you something.
不  重点是  它就是我
No, that's the whole point. It is me.
如果你说的你  是想说比你更好  我同意
If by you, you mean much better than you.
看见没  我说什么来着
See? What did I tell you?
唐娜  我是认真的
Donna, I'm serious.
听着  这东西确实很有趣
Look, this is a really cute joke,
但我能不能和我的朋友谈一谈
but can I please just have a conversation with my friend?
如果指朋友  你是想说
If by friend, you mean--
当然了  瑞秋
Of course you can, Rachel.
你需要什么
What do you need?
我理理清楚
So let me get this straight,
你爱上了一个女人
you're in love with a woman
你们才刚刚认识
that you've known for about ten minutes.
她已经有了别的男人的孩子
She's having another man's baby,
尽管如此  你还要娶她
and yet, you're gonna marry her,
然后把孩子当做自己的养
and raise it as your own.
简而言之是这样
In a nutshell.
你想从我这知道点什么
What exactly do you want from me?
我需要你的意见
I need your advice.
明天做B超的时候那家伙会在场
The guy's gonna be at the sonogram tomorrow,
我怕我到时候当众闹事
and I'm afraid I may cause a scene.
路易  我不明白你找我干什么
Louis, I don't understand what you're coming to me for.
-我又不懂...  -这就是原因
- What do I know about - Here, this is why.
明白了吗
Yeah, you get it?
这就是我找你的原因
This is why I'm coming to you.
他长得挺帅的
Oh, he's good-looking.
他不只是长得帅
He's not just good-looking.
他简直就是文艺复兴时期的雕塑
He's a goddamn Renaissance statue.
我需要知道他怎么想的
And I need to know what he's thinking.
路易  我代表不了所有的帅哥
Louis, I don't speak for all handsome men.
当你见到我的时候你看到了什么
What do you see when you look at me?
什么
What?
我想知道你见到我的时候看到了什么
I wanna know what you see when you look at me.
就现在  说实话
Right now, be honest.
前三个从你脑海里蹦出的词
Say the first three things that pop into your head.
-牙齿鼻子牙齿  -该死  严肃点
- Teeth, nose, teeth. - God damn it! Be serious.
我是认真的
I am being serious.
好吧  你知道吗...
Well, you know what--
算了  我就不该找你
Never mind. I shouldn't have come to you.
路易  我看到了什么不重要
Louis, it doesn't matter what I see.
重要的是这个女人能看到了什么
What matters is what this woman sees,
她显然是看到了什么
and she obviously sees something,
不然不会和你在一起
or she wouldn't be with you.
而是和他在一起了
She'd be with him.
谢谢你  哈维  但是你了解我
Look, I appreciate that, Harvey, but you know me.
我要和那个男的共处一室
I'm gonna be in the same room as him,
看着他们俩结晶的图像
looking at an image of what he made with her.
我要怎么控制住自己
How do I not lose my shit?
你说的没错  这是他的孩子
You're right. It is his baby.
但这也是你的
But it's yours too.
你会想让宝宝得到的爱越多越好
And you're gonna want it to have as much love as it possibly can,
这意味着你要处理好和它生父的关系
and that means having a good relationship with its father,
因为没有什么比家人更重要了
because there's nothing more important than family.
你说得对
You're right.
谢谢你  哈维
Thank you, Harvey.
迈克  大伙怎么样了
Hey, Mike. How's it going out there?
有什么需要吗
What can I do for you?
我想让你看下这个
I want you to take a look at this.
我理理清楚
Let me get this straight,
你想让奥利佛去去向法院申请
you want Oliver to petition the court
-让玛莉莎为他的案子辩护  -是的
- to let Marissa argue his case. - Yes, I do.
-但那不可能  -为什么
- Well, that's not gonna happen. - Why not?
因为他是经过训练的律师
'Cause he's a full-fledged attorney,
而玛莉莎是一个法学院三年级学生
and she's a third-year law student.
他上法庭会慌的
He gets flustered in court.
而她从来就没上过庭
And she's never even been to court.
我要跟你说我觉得他搞不定这件案子
I'm telling you that I don't think that he can handle this.
她能搞定  此时这个女人的未来悬于一线
She can, and this woman's future is on the line.
那就说服她接受协议
Then convince her to take the deal.
她不想要这份协议
She doesn't want the deal.
你这是为难我  迈克
Putting me in a hell of a spot here, Mike.
纳森  你不是平白无故雇我的
Nathan, you hired me for a reason.
你告诉我管理这些人
You told me to run the associates,
我也正在这么做
and I'm running them.
那现在你到底让不让我做
Now, are you gonna let me do that or not?
你要做  就去做
You're gonna do it, do it,
但你自己去跟奥利佛说
but you're gonna be the one to tell Oliver.
你要见我
You wanted to see me?
是的  请进
Yeah, I, uh--I did. Come in.
我想跟你说下索菲亚・普莱斯的案子
I want to talk to you about the, uh, Sofia Price case.
好极了  因为我还要告诉你
Great, because I actually wanted to tell you about
新泽西州有五起相似案件都赢得了大笔和解费
five similar cases in New Jersey that won huge settlements.
干得好  我们用得上
That's good work, and we can use that.
不过我需要你做些事情
But listen, I need you to do something for me.
你想让玛莉莎作为主辩
You want Marissa to be first chair.
我觉得这样最好
I think it's for the best.
迈克  我知道为什么你觉得这要更好
Mike, I know why you think this is the right choice,
-但我能做好  -对不起  奥利佛
- but I can do this. - I'm sorry, Oliver,
但在你现在的工作状态
but at this point in your career,
我觉得你做不到
I don't think you can.
-迈克  -奥利佛
- Mike. - Oliver--
你自己都说  你在庭上会慌
you said it yourself-you get flustered in court.
我知道  但如果我要成为一个真正的律师
I know that, but if I'm going to be a real lawyer,
我必须在庭上要表现的更好
I have to get better in trial,
而唯一的办法就是重装上阵
and the only way to do that is to get back on the horse.
我跟你说等接到合适的案子
And I'm telling you that when the right case comes along,
我保证让你上
I promise I will let you do that,
但这个案子不合适
but this is not the case.
这个是玛莉莎的
This one's Marissa's,
我需要你支持她
and I need to know you have her back.
我会的
I do.
很好
Good.
我去告诉她
I'll go tell her.
你不必这么做  奥利佛
You don't have to do that, Oliver.
我必须这么做
Yes, I do.
这样对诊所更好
It's better for the clinic
让她认为这是因为我对她有信心
if she thinks I have confidence in her,
而不是你对我没信心
not that you don't have confidence in me.
-你回来了  -你最好相信我回来了
- You're back. - You better believe I'm back,
因为我查了下你在搞什么鬼
because I looked into what you're doing
还有背后原因
and why you're doing it.
没有什么好查的  斯佩克特先生
There's really not much to find, Mr. Specter.
我来替你说吧
Well, let me lay it out for you.
极速数据处理公司偷了你的技术
Velocity Data Solutions stole your technology,
他们急着出售
and they're rushing it to market,
所以你想策划一个收购计划
so you want to orchestrate a takeover
来拿回属于你的东西  我说的对吗
and get back what's yours. That sound about right?
我的公司要垮了  就因为他们所做的事情
My company is gonna go under, because of what they did.
很多人会失业
People are gonna lose their jobs.
那就去找联调局
Then go to the FBI.
-我不能去  -为什么
- I can't. - Why not?
因为我不能
Because I can't.
行  我跟你说为什么你不能去
Yeah, I'll tell ya why you can't.
因为除非你别无选择
Because a squeaky clean guy like you
不然你这样身家清白的人不会来找我这样的人
doesn't come to a guy like me unless he's got no choice,
你需要我的程度远远超过
and you need me a hell of a lot more
我需要你  所以等你准备好说实情
than I need you, so why don't you give me a call
再给我打电话吧
when you're ready to tell the truth.
他们从我这里得到的技术
They got it from me.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
我出过轨
I had an affair.
我很笨很不小心  让她登入我的电脑
I was stupid and careless, and she got access to my laptop.
而你已婚了
And you're married,
不能让你老婆发现这件事
and your wife can't find out about it,
所以你不能去找联调局
and that's why you can't go to the FBI.
就是这样  现在你清楚了
There, now you know.
我只知道瑞秋・赞恩有资格成为律师
What I know is Rachel Zane deserves to be in the Bar,
你不仅不能阻止她
so you're not only gonna stop blocking her,
如果有人阻止她你还要出面干预
you're gonna run interference for her if someone else does.
我无权这么做
I don't have the power to do that.
胡扯  你有权阻止
Bullshit. You had the power to stop it,
你最好能扭转态势
and you better believe that you can turn it the other direction.
作为回报  你会做我让你做的事
And in return, you'll do what I want.
不
No.
你得这么做  因为这样是对的
You're gonna do it, because it's the right thing to do.
但我会为了其他事情帮你
But I'll do what you want for something else.
我有事找你谈
I need to talk to you.
什么事
What's going on?
奥利佛把所有索菲亚的案子的文件给了我
Oliver just gave me all the case files for Sofia.
他说我应该把这事做到底
He said I'm the one who should bring this home.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们谈过了  我也赞同他的想法
We talked about it, and I agree with him.
迈克  我知道这不是奥利佛的注意
Mike, I know this wasn't Oliver's idea.
这是你的主意
It was yours.
因为你觉得他没有准备好
'Cause you don't think he's ready.
我也是为此来找你
Which is why I'm coming to you.
-玛莉莎  你能搞定  -我知道我能搞定
- Marissa, you can handle this. - I know I can,
但问题是我不能这么做
but the problem is I can't do it.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我父亲患病多时
Um, my father's been sick,
我一直闭口不谈  是因为我不喜欢
and I haven't talked about it, because I don't like to...
但他现在需要做手术
But now he needs surgery,
我几周前就提出休假了
and I put in for the time off weeks ago,
我必须在那儿陪着他
and I have to be there for him,
但现在我准备告诉你
but now that I'm telling you this,
我觉得或许我可以提早几天飞回来
I'm thinking maybe I could fly back a few days early,
-或者我可以晚一天再去  -别说了
- or I could get there a day later - Stop, stop, stop.
没事
It's okay.
-我想帮索菲娅  迈克  -我知道你想
- I wanna help Sofia, Mike. - I know you do.
但你需要陪着你父亲
But you need to be with your father.
那你怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我会想出办法的
I'll figure something out.
唐娜  你好  你喜欢那个
Donna, hey, how did you like the--
不行
It's a no.
"不行"是什么意思
What do you mean it's a no?
我是说这东西很有趣  但我没兴趣
I mean it's a cute joke, but I'm not interested
把它看作一个商机
in pursuing it as a business opportunity.
我不理解  我以为你喜欢这个想法
I don't understand. I thought you liked the idea.
的确  但那是在我意识到
I did, but that was before I realized
它只会说点俏皮话和时评之前
that it was nothing but quippy lines and sassy remarks.
但那就是你
But that's who you are.
不  本杰明
No, Benjamin.
那是我的其中一面
That's part of who I am,
你所看到的那面
and that's the only part you've ever seen,
但那是因为我们俩并不了解彼此
but that's because we don't really know each other.
但若我们了解彼此  你会知道我真正的特长
But if we did, you'd know that what really makes me special
是我的直觉和同情心
is my intuition and my empathy
以及我的真心
and my heart,
而这里都没有  所以
and this doesn't have any of that, so...
我很抱歉  但是不行
I'm sorry, but it's a no.
迈克
Mike.
我很想现在聊聊  但是不行
I'd love to chat right now, but I can't.
我正准备看个电影换换心情
I'm actually going to a movie for a change.
好  我只占用你一点时间
Yeah, I just need a second.
什么事
What's up?
明天的普莱斯案我想让你来做辩护
I need you to argue the Price case tomorrow.
你刚才说想让我干嘛  因为听起来好像
What'd you just ask me? Because it sounded like
在你让我接手前求我让给玛莉莎的
you want me to take the case that you begged me
-案子  -我确实让她接手了
- to give to Marissa. - I did give it to her,
但你没告诉我她父亲要动手术
but you didn't tell me that her father had surgery.
因为我不知道她父亲要动手术
Because I didn't know her father had surgery.
她提申请了
She put in for it.
我才不管这种烂事
And I don't pay attention to that shit.
-让奥利佛来接手  -我告诉过你他会输的
- Give it back to Oliver. - I told you he'll lose.
-那就输掉吧  -抱歉  我得走了
- Then he'll lose. Now I'm sorry, but I have to go.
该死  这事关一个女人的一生
God damn it, this is a woman's life,
而你却要去看什么电影
and you're going to a goddamn movie.
你到底怎么回事
What the hell is wrong with you?
你是在
Are you f--
听着  我们在家法律诊所工作
Listen, we work in a clinic.
我们每位当事人的生活都岌岌可危
Every one of our client's lives is hanging by a thread,
如果他们输了  他们会流离失所
and if they lose, they're out on the street,
他们不能做手术  也可能被驱赶出境
they don't get the surgery, or they get deported.
那才是生活
That's life.
我已经五年没享受生活了
And I haven't had a life in five years,
这是我雇你的原因
which is why I hired you,
所以别再和我说那些
so don't you ever say that to me again.
听着  我们只能请到奥利佛这样的律师
Look, Oliver's the kind of lawyer we get here.
如果他解决不了  那就解决不了
If he can't handle it, he can't handle it.
只能这样了
That's how it goes.
那么我会向法庭请求坐他的旁席
Then I wanna petition the court to sit at the table with him.
不行
No.
我们可以请求特殊豁免
We can ask for a special exemption, and--
我的回答是不行  听见了吗
And I said no, all right?
你又不是法庭人员
You're not an officer of the court.
他们不会同意  那也不再是你该做的
They will not grant it, and that is not your place here.
那么至少我可以坐在他旁边  我可以
Then at least I can sit near him, and I can--
你现在给我听好了
You hear me right now!
我因为所需  才给了你一次机会
I gave you a chance, because I needed it,
但如果你为了一个租房案
but if you risk the reputation of this clinic
拿这家法律诊所的名声冒险  我就让你走人
over one housing case, I will fire you
并且保证你以后
and make sure that you are banned from
再难在法庭立足
ever sitting foot in a courtroom again.
听清楚了吗
Is that clear?
-听清楚了吗  -好
- Is that clear? - Yes.
听清楚了
It's clear.
你这地方"不错"
This is a nice place you got here.
准备什么时候报废
When are they condemning it?
你来这儿干嘛  哈维
What are you doing here, Harvey?
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
现在不是时候  我得想明白怎么
Now's not a good time. I gotta figure out how--
如果我告诉你我有办法让你拿到律师资格呢
What if I told you I have a way to get you into the Bar?
什么
What?
有人想在我们面前对
Someone came to us trying to play games
瑞秋的品行考核面试做手脚
with Rachel's Character and Fitness interview and--
等等  你在说什么
Wait, what--what the hell are you talking about?
放松  我处理好了
Relax, I handled it,
但现在我们有机会让你也参加考核
but now we have a chance to get you in.
有什么条件
What's the catch?
迈克
Mike...
哈维  天下没有免费的午餐
Harvey, there are no free lunches.
有什么条件
What's the catch?
我们要对极速数据处理公司提起诉讼
We need to come up with a lawsuit against
使他们的股价下跌
Velocity Data Solutions to drive their stock price down.
你在开玩笑吗  不行
Are you kidding me? No.
不行是什么意思  你怎么了
What do you mean no? What--what's wrong with you?
我的问题是我真的不想
What's wrong with me is I don't particularly feel like
再回监狱了  而且我记得
going back to prison, and the last time I checked,
制造诉讼来操控股价是违法的
fabricating a lawsuit to manipulate a stock is illegal.
我们找个正当的诉讼理由就不算违法
It's not illegal if we find a legitimate suit.
这都是胡扯
That is such bullshit
那只是我们告诉自己的屁话
that we'd just be telling ourselves that,
就像我们告诉自己我们并没有和卡荷尔串通一样
just like we told ourselves we weren't colluding with Cahill.
那让你逃离了牢狱之灾
And that got you out of prison,
所以我们把这差事搞定
so let's finish the job,
恢复你的律师资格
and get you back to being a lawyer.
哈维  我现在比以前更像个律师
Harvey, I'm more a lawyer now than I ever was.
胡扯  你知道你就是个保姆
Oh, bullshit, you're a babysitter and you know it.
我在做我想做的事  我在帮助别人
Hey, I'm doing what I wanted, and I'm helping people,
所以如果你想把我当成保姆
so if you wanna call me a babysitter,
随你的便  但是现在房子着火了
you go right ahead, but right now the house is on fire,
孩子们都在卧室里
the kids are in the bedroom,
我他妈的会救他们的
and I'm about to goddamn save them.
迈克  我们现在遇到了机会
Mike, we have an opportunity right now.
再也不会出现这样的机会了
It's not gonna present itself again.
我很感激  哈维
I appreciate that, Harvey.
真的
I do.
但是我告诉你  我的回答是不
But I'm telling you, my answer is no.
怎么了
Hey, what's going on?
出现什么紧急情况了  玛莉莎呢
What's the emergency? Where's Marissa?
玛莉莎走了
Marissa's gone.
走了是什么意思
What do you mean gone?
我的意思是你明天是首席辩护人
I mean that you're first chair tomorrow,
我们得让你做好准备
and we need to get you ready.
什么
What?
-奥利佛  这没什么大不了的  -没什么大不了
- Oliver, it's not a big deal. - Not a big deal?
我们不能冒险让我再在法庭上搞砸了
We can't risk having me mess up in court again.
这个案子太重要了  你知道我是如何知道的吗
This case is too important. You know how I know that?
-是你告诉我的  -我知道我说过什么
- Because you told me. - I know what I said.
但是我们没有时间找别人了
But we don't have time to find anyone else.
明天就庭审了
The trial's tomorrow.
我们到底要不要做这件事
Now, are we gonna do this thing or not?
我第一次参加模拟法庭时出了件事
It happened at my first mock trial.
我准备得很充分
I was so prepared.
庭审开始
And then trial started,
对方提出了一个我没准备的问题
and the other side threw a wrinkle in.
我觉得我能随机应变
And I thought I could think on my feet,
但是突然间  我觉得所有人都在看着我
but all of a sudden, I felt everyone watching me,
我口干舌燥  大脑一片空白
and my mouth went dry, and my mind went blank,
我就愣住了
and I froze.
奥利佛...
Oliver...
我们可以一起渡过这个难关的
we can get through this together.
但你已经告诉过我我搞不定
Except now you told me I can't handle it,
那就像给我的大脑钻了个洞
and that's gonna be boring a hole in my brain,
让这事难了上千倍
making this thing a thousand times harder.
我不能收回我说过的话
Well, I can't take back what I said,
但是我能做的是整晚待在这
but what I can do is stay here all night
确保你证明我错了
to make sure you prove me wrong.
我不知道
I don't know.
你知道的
Yes, you do.
我想让你说出来
I want you to say it.
我们会赢下这个案子
We're gonna win this.
We're going to win this.
再说一遍
Say it again.
我们会赢下这个案子
We're going to win this.
再说一次
One more time,
用上点真心
but this time mean it.
我们会赢下这个案子
We are going to win this.
他们要做的第一件事
Now, the first thing they're gonna do
-就是提出撤案动议  -事实上  他们已经这么做了
- is file a motion to dismiss. - Actually, they already did.
很好  那咱们来搞定这件事
Good. Let's work on that.
抱歉  我迟到了
Hey. Sorry I'm late.
我中途下车给约书亚买了个礼物
I had to stop off and get Joshua a present,
因为我想欢迎他加入我们这个大家庭
'cause I wanted to welcome him into the family.
路易  那好贴心啊
Louis, that is so sweet,
但是约书亚来不了了
but it turns out Joshua can't make it.
什么叫他来不了
What do you mean he can't make it?
本来他要飞过来的  但是工作上发生了点事
He was gonna fly in, but something came up with work,
所以他取消了航班
so he canceled his flight.
这他妈是个什么样的父亲啊
What the hell kind of father is that?
-路易  -简直扯淡
- Louis-- - This is bullshit.
这是他的骨肉
It's his flesh and his blood,
如果他想当孩子的爸爸  他得成为一个爸爸
and if he's gonna be father, he needs to be a father.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
你一开始甚至都不想他出现在这里
You didn't even want him to be here in the first place.
我现在想了
Well, I want him here now.
路易  我原以为你比这更宽容
Louis, I thought you were a more forgiving person than this.
我还以为你想让孩子和它的生父
And I thought you wanted our baby to have a relationship
能够建立感情
with its biological father.
他会的
And he's going to.
但是如果你遇到像今天这样的事
But if you're gonna get this worked up
就这么激动的话
about something like this,
让我觉得我根本不了解你
it makes me think I don't really know you.
路易  你能老实告诉我  你真的了解我吗
Louis, can you honestly tell me that you really know me?
准备好做B超了吗
Are we ready to take a picture?
我不了解
No, I don't.
现在我觉得我毁了我们的兴致  所以...
And now I feel like I'm ruining this, so...
如果你不想让我和你进去  我就不进去了
if you don't want me to come in with you, I won't.
也许最好还是我自己一个人进去做
Maybe it's best if I just do this myself.
法官大人  这件事发生在三天前
Your Honor, this incident occurred three nights ago,
而那孩子有哮喘史
yet the boy has a history of asthma,
就说明哮喘和开工没关系
proving one has nothing to do with the other.
这些医院记录显示
These hospital records show
他的肺部有易碎的建筑材料
friable construction material in his lungs.
是怎么进入他的肺部呢
How did it get there?
可能是从100种不同的地方进入的
It could have gotten there from a hundred different places.
这个案子完全基于猜测
This case is based entirely on speculation,
应该被撤销
and it should be dismissed.
这个案子是基于你的客户
This case is based on the fact that your client
在租户还未搬走就开始动工这一事实
started construction while tenants were still in the building,
违反了房地产法令
in violation of the Real Estate Code.
如果我告诉你普莱斯女士同意了呢
And what if I told you Ms. Price signed off on this?
我会说那是不可能的  因为她没有
I'd say that's not possible, because she didn't.
你有你的文件
Well, you've got documents,
我有我的
and I have one too.
这是一份证明书复件
This is a copy of a certified letter
三周前由我的委托人提供给
from my client to the remaining tenants
在租租户
three weeks ago,
明确声明将开始装修工程
stating that construction will begin,
向所有住户提供了明确警告
giving fair warning to the occupants.
法官大人  我的委托人并未看过文件
Your Honor, my client's never seen that.
她也许是没看
Well, she might not have seen it,
-但她收到了  -收到也不代表她打开了
- but she got it. - It doesn't mean she opened it,
或者她就看了
or--or even read it.
法律规定  她看没看不重要
According to the city, that doesn't matter.
建筑法规305-A款
Building Code 305-A:
"建筑施工需以证明书形式
"Tenants are required to be notified
通知所有租户"
of all construction by certified letter."
你说这算不算证明书
Is this a certified letter or not?
该死的  奥利佛  说它不可采用
God damn it, Oliver, say it's inadmissible.
它是算  但是...
Yes, it is, but--
所以你承认了她被通知过
So you admit that she was notified,
所以我的委托人不该为此负责
and therefore my client should be absolved of all liability.
我没有...
I--I don't--I--
反对
Objection!
法官大人  这就是开庭前我跟您
Your Honor, this is the fraudulent attorney
提过的那个欺诈律师
I spoke with you about before trial.
我们请求禁止他在庭上发言
We ask that he either refrain from speaking,
或者责令其离开法庭
or be removed from the court
并且判决支持被告方
with an immediate ruling for the defense.
允许
Request granted.
先生  你再在庭上开口
Sir, open your mouth in my courtroom again,
就会被逐出法庭  案子也会被撤销
and you will be removed, and this case will be dismissed.
格雷迪先生  你是否要
Mr. Grady, do you have an objection
反对约翰逊小姐的陈述
to Ms. Johnson's statement or not?
不  对不起  我不反对
I don't. I'm sorry, I don't.
那法庭别无选择
Then the court has no choice
只能判决有偏见驳回起诉
but to dismiss this case with prejudice.
本杰明  你别问了  我说过了...
Benjamin, before you ask, I already told you--
要是我能让它更像你呢
What if I could make it more like you?
什么意思
What do you mean?
你说你最特殊的地方
You said what makes you special
在于你的直觉  同情和心
is your intuition, your empathy, and your heart.
要是我能让它拥有这些呢
What if I could make it have that?
这怎么可能做到
How could you possibly do that?
就像我能给它
The same way I gave it the ability
学习俏皮话的能力一样  也许我能
to learn from your quips, I might be able to give it
让它学到你的心
the ability to learn from your heart,
但这需要你的帮助
but it would require your help.
你真的觉得这可能吗
You really think we could do that?
不知道  但我觉得值得一试
I don't know, but I know we can try.
那你需要了解的第一件事就是
Well, then the first thing that you need to learn
永远  永远不许坐我的椅子
is never, ever, ever sit in my chair.
抱歉  我...
Oh, I'm sorry, I--I was--
镇定  本杰明  我只是在逗你
Relax, Benjamin, I'm just messing with you.
-但是从我的椅子上起来  -好的
- But get out of my chair. - Yeah.
路易  你怎么来了
Louis, what-- what are you doing here?
我有东西给你
I need to bring you a few things.
这都是什么
What is all that?
高中年鉴  童年相簿
High school yearbooks, childhood photo albums,
还有成长过程七个精彩时刻中
and six out of seven of the highlight reels
被妈妈照下来的六张照片
my mother shot of us growing up.
少的那张是怎么回事
What happened to the seventh?
那个夏天犯了点事
Oh... summer of D&D.
如果你不介意的话
And if it's all the same to you,
我希望你不会不愿跟我上床了
I would like to still be able to have sex again.
-路易  -你说得对
- Louis-- - You were right.
我们确实还不了解对方的所有
We don't know everything about each other,
但我们应该做的是更深入的了解对方
but that just means we need to get to know each other better,
而有什么能比一起做抚养孩子的准备
and what better way to get to know each other
能更好的让我们了解对方呢
then by preparing to bring our child into the world?
路易  如果这就是你对今天下午的事的回应
Louis, if this is your reaction to what we went through today,
那我想我已经更加了解你了
I feel like I know you better already.
说到今天下午的事
Speaking of what we went through today,
情况如何
how'd it go?
不如你带我回家
Why don't you take me home,
我好好给你讲
and I'll tell you all about it.
哈维  我能跟你谈谈吗
Harvey, can I talk to you for a second?
当然  瑞秋  怎么了
Sure, Rachel. What's going on?
是关于我跟
It's about my interview with
品行考核委员会的面试
the Character and Fitness committee.
-怎么了  -路易想骗我来着
- What about it? - Louis tried to lie to me.
他说只是搞错了文件
He said it was some sort of mix-up,
但我问唐娜时
but when I asked Donna about it,
她跟我说去跟他们
she told me that you were the one
谈的人是你  不是路易
who went to see that man for me, not Louis.
哈维  没事的  你可以告诉我
Look, Harvey, it's okay, you can tell me.
是因为迈克  是不是
It was about Mike, wasn't it?
不是  是为了筹码
No, it was about leverage.
什么意思
What do you mean?
那个阻止你面试的人
The guy holding up your interview
想让我们帮他办件事
was trying to get us to do something,
因为他以为能威胁到我们
because he thought he could.
那你要帮他办吗
Are you going to?
要  他要
Yes. He is.
你说的是我想的那个意思吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
是的
Yeah.
我答应
I'm in.